Guide to the Black Stone Press: papers and ephemera, 1974-1996
Department of Special Collections
Black Stone Press: papers and ephemera,
1974-1996
Special Collections M0892
Koch, Peter.
7.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1996 and 1997.
Biography
The Black Stone Press was located in Missoula, Montana, from 1974-1978. It then moved to San Francisco. In 1982 the press was renamed Peter Koch, Printer, and in 1984 it moved from San Francisco to Oakland. Following the 1989 Loma Prieta earthquake, the press again relocated, this time to Berkeley.
Scope and Content
Included are Peter Koch's work from 1975 through 1996. The archive contains works of poets and other authors that Stanford collects, and complements other library holdings by Koch and other fine presses of the American West. Among its approximately 1300 items are invitations, announcements, business cards and stationery, books, prints, broadsides, and related ephemera. It does not include MONTANA GOTHIC, Peter Koch's literary tri-quarterly which was published 1974-78.
Access Terms
Thomas, David, 1947 Apr. 1-; Poage, Michael, 1945-; Sund, Robert, 1929-; Pagliari, Ulisse.; Hawks, Nelson Crocker, 1840-1929.; Severson, Elizabeth H.; Silloway, Mary H.; Koshland, Daniel Edward, Jr.; Elliot, James Welsh.; Forbes, David W.; Odegaard, Charles E.; Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-; Guest, Barbara.; Fuller, June.; Andrews, Adolphus, Jr.; Rothenberg, Michael.; Davenport, Guy.; Wemyss, Nina.; Clark, Tom.; Southwick, Albert B.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Kyle-Brown, Ann.; Baxter, A. W.; Koch, Elers.; Fields, Ann.; Brautigan, Richard.; Licko, Zuzana, 1961-; Morris,Charles Kendrick.; Maje, Malles.; White, Kerr L.; Rutkow, Ira M.; Browne, Hablot Knight, 1815-1882.; Nations, Opal L.; Rexroth, Kenneth, 1905-; D'Alessandro, Pat.; Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-; Duncan, Robert.; Atwood, Margaret.; Transtomer, Tomas.; Argento, Dominick.; Aplon, Roger, 1937-; Levertov, Denise, 1923-; Antinova, Eleanora.; Rilke, Rainer Maria, 1875-1926.; Gilbert, Sandra M.; Von dem Bussche, Wolf.; Waters, Alice.; Smart, Christopher, 1722-1771.; Mason, J. H. (John Henry), 1875-1951.; Gleason, Molly.; Stent, Mary.; Levinson, Joel D.; Folberg, Neil.; Scheiwiller, Vanni.; Scheiwiller, Giovanni.; Pagnol, Marcel, 1895-1974.; Frederick, Molly.; Peters, Nancy J. (Nancy Joyce).; Fisher, M. F. K. (Mary Frances Kennedy), 1908-; Gilhooly, David.; Brower, David R.; Beck, Alan.; Walters, Sylvia Solochek.; Burdette, Robert J. (Robert Jones), 1844-1914.; Marlis, Stefanie, 1951-; Seibert, Richard.; Bernhard, Ruth.; Horn, Holly.; Kinnell, Galway, 1927-; Snyder, Gary, 1930-; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962.; Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900.; Sanchez, Thomas.; Gifford, Barry, 1946-; Acosta Hernandez, Juvenal.; Black Stone Press.; Peter Koch, Printer.; Book Club of California.; Hormone Derange Editions.; Philippe Bonnafant Gallery.; Gleeson Library Associates.; Richard A. Gleeson Library (University of San Francisco).; Bancroft Library. Friends.; Zamorano Club.; Roxburghe Club.; Missoula Museum of the Arts.; California Historical Society.; Jesuit School of Theology at Berkeley.; Printing--California.
Container List
- 1975-76, 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Includes: BSP letterhead stationery, BSP business cards, poetry broadsides, broadsides for Montana Gothic, lithograph.
- 1977, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - David Thomas. Fossil Fuel. Missoula: Montana Writers Collective, 1977.
  - Persian Rugs, May 8-June 28 1977.Missoula Museum of Art. Missoula: Black Stone Press, 1977.
- 1977, 23 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes: BSP business cards and notecards, business cards from businesses in Missoula, MT, book marks, ex libris cards, 1 lithograph.
- 1978, 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes: Stationery and broadsides documenting BSP's move from Missoula, MT to San Francisco, 1978.
- 1978, 26 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes: BSP business cards, business cards from businesses in Missoula and SF, notecards.
- 1979, 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes: exhibit publications for North Point Gallery, stationery for BSP and for other concerns.
- 1979, 32 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes: business cards, BSP prospecti, Book Club of California and Roxburghe Club cards, "The Reckoning" poem by Richard Silberg.
- 1979, 1 item: (Box 1, Folder 4)
  program for Wayzgoose 1979, a symposium for contemporary bookbinding held in SF, August, 1979.
- 1980, 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes: marriage announcements, stationery, opera programs, dust jacket.
- 1980, 21 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes: business cards, exhibit broadsides, "Five Poems" by Michael Poage. Includes announcement of BSP's move to 865 Florida St., SF.
- 1981, 23 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes: business cards, announcements from Gleeson Library, BSP, and Book Club of California.
- 1982, 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes stationery, event announcements.
- 1982, 37 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes: business cards, event invitations and announcements, gallery invitations.
- 1982, 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Robert Sund. This flower! La Conner: The Great Blue Heron Society, 1982.
  - Jeffrey Thomas Fine & Rare Books, catalogue I, 1982.
  - Philippe Bonnafant Gallery. Second Annual Exhibit of Works on Paper by Recent Graduates of Architecture Schools, 1982.
  - Ulisse Pagliari. Fifteen High Relief Ceramic Tableaux, inspired by E.T.A. Hoffman's tale Princess Brambilla. SF: Philippe Bonnafant, 1982.
- 1982
  Also see materials in Box 3 (OS)
- 1983, 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  1 piece of stationery.
  - Nelson C. Hawks. Explanation of the Point System of Printing Type...BSP, 1983.
  - Elizabeth H, Severson, Poems, 1983.
- 1983, 26 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes: business cards (Peter Coyote), prospecti, Gleeson Library Associates materials.
- 1984, 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes: stationery, map noting Peter Koch's new building in Oakland.
- 1984, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - It's Just the Truth, the Incomplete Collection of the Public Moments of Howard A. Friedman. Publ. By PKF-EFF. SF: Peter Koch, 1984.
- 1984, 30 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes: business cards, marriage and birth announcements, Gleeson Library Associates announcements, broadside ephemera.
- 1985, 15 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes: business ephemera, stationery, poetry broadside.
- 1985, 37 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes: stationery, business cards. Poetry broadsides, Gleeson Library Associates announcements.
- 1985, 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - International Association of Bibliophiles, XIVth Congress, the San Francisco Program, October 6-October 11, 1985.
  - Rare Book and Manuscript Collections in the Libraries of the San Francisco Bay Area. Comp. and Ed. by Mary H. Silloway.
  - Foolish Compromise, additional Poetry and Prose. Daniel Edward Koshland, Jr. Berkeley:Full Court Press, 1985.
  - Taylor & Taylor, a Reminiscence. James Welsh Elliot. SF: the Kimble Collection, 1985.
- 1986, 17 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes: stationery, Gleeson Library Associates announcements, poetry broadsides.
- 1986, 41 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes: stationery, Gleeson Library Associates announcements, poetry broadsides, business cards, invitations.
- 1986, 2 items: (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "An Act to Prohibit Hawaiians from Emigrating to California 'Where they may Die in Misery." By David W. Forbes. Oakland: Peter Koch, 1986.
  - Dear Doctor, a Personal Letter to a Physician. Charles E. Odegaard. Menlo Park, CA: Henry J. Kaiser Foundation, 1986.
- 1987, 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes: Prospecti, stationery, Gleeson Library Associates announcements.
- 1987, 32 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes: business cards, invitations, Gleeson Library Associates announcements.
- 1987, 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes: broadsides.
- 1988, 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Includes: stationery, invitations, Gleeson Library Associates announcements.
- 1988, 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  "The House Cleaning Company" publication.
- 1988, 31 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1988, 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1 broadside.
  - "Emperor Norton & Hawaii." David W. Forbes. Oakland: Peter Koch, 1988.
- 1988, 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Striking Research Gold, Distinguished Collections in California Independent Academic Libraries," Foreword by L.C. Powell. Calfornia Private Academic Libraries, 1988.
  - "Howard A. Friedman, 1919-1988." Funeral keepsake.
  - "Musicality," Barbara Guest and June Fuller. Kelset St. Press, 1988.
  - "Reminiscences," Adolphus Andrews, Jr. 7 unbound signatures.
- 1988
- 1989, 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes: Gleeson Library Associates materials, stationery.
- 1989, 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes: Business advertisements, booklet from the Conference on the Underrepresentation of Minorities in the Medical and other Health Professions, Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, 1986, "Howard A. Friedman, 1919-1988." Funeral keepsake.
- 1989, 21 items. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Includes: business cards, materials from Gleeson Library Associates, Bancroft Friends of the Library, Roxburghe Club.
- 1990, 15 Items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes: stationery.
- 1990, 22 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes: stationery, business cards, Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates announcements.
- 1990, 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Advertising broadside for "Favorite Songs" by Michael Rothenberg.
  - Advertising broadside and publication of the fragments of Herakleitos with accompanying transl. by Guy Davenport.
- 1990, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Soul of the Vine, Wine in Literature. ed. by Nina Wemyss. Oakville: Robert Mondavi Winery, 1994.
- 1991, 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Includes: Roxburghe Club and Gleeson Library Associates materials, stationery.
- 1991, 37 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Includes: business cards, stationery, Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials, prospecti.
  Tom Clark. Little Canto, San Francisco: New College of California, 1991.
- 1991, 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  3 numbered lithographs: "Froze," "Broke," and "Hard" by Peter Koch, 1991.
- 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Albert B. Southwick. The Johnson Family of Hyde Park & Sag Harbor. Carmel: Sea Change Press, 1991. P. Koch, printer.
- 1992, 14 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Includes: stationery, business materials, Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials, prospecti.
- 1992, 23 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Includes: business cards, stationery, invitations, Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials.
- 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Lawrence Ferlinghetti. A Sea Voyage. Limited edition of 35 copies, printed under direction of Peter Koch, 1992.
- 1992, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Menu from Sept. 19, 1992 joint meeting of Roxburghe & Zamorano clubs.
- 1993, 8 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Includes: stationery, Gleeson Library Associates broadsides.
- 1993, 31 items. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Includes: business cards, Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials, various announcements, "Diogenes sat in the Public Square on afternoon Glueing Shut the Pages of a Book," printed by Peter Koch.
- 1993, 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Book Club of California Quarterly News Letter, Vol LIX, No. 1, Winter, 1993
  - Exploring the Edge, Guisiniani's account of Columbus in the margins of the 1516 Polyglot Psalter. Berkeley: Bancroft Library Press, 1993.Limited edition of 35 copies printed under the direction of Peter Koch.
  - "The Ballad of Alastair Poltroon," Whut the Press.
- 1993, 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  4 poetry broadsides by Ann Kyle-Brown and A.W. Baxter, 1 broadside announcing the establishment of William Everson's Equinox Press.
- 1994, 13 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1994, 34 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Includes: stationery, business cards, Friends of the Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials, announcements of Peter Koch exhibits.
- 1994, 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Elers Koch. Lumberjacks & Cowboys. Berkeley: Bancroft Library Press, 1994.Limited edition of 35 copies printed under the direction of Peter Koch.
  - Diogenes sat in the public square one afternoon glueing shut the pages of a book. Text broadsides.
  - Book Club of California Quarterly News Letter. Vol LIX, Spring, Summer, and Fall 1994.
  - Prospectus and publication announcement of Soul of the Vine.
  - Prospectus and publication announcement of Unsought Intimaces, Peter Koch, 1994.
- 1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  The Collected Poems of Ann Fields, ed. by Michael Rothenberg, intro. by William Dickey. Pacifica, CA: Big Bridge Press, 1994. Jacket design by Peter Koch.
- 1995, 18 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Includes: stationery, Friends of the Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials.
- 1995, 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Richard Brautigan. Would you like to saddle up a couple of goldfish and swim to Alaska. Berkeley: Bancroft Library Press, 1995. Limited edition of 50 copies printed under the direction of Peter Koch.
  - Exhibit catalog fom "Peter Koch, Printer, recent work, Widener Memorial Room Rotunda, May 3-31, 1995"
- 1995, 33 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Includes: stationery, invitations, business cards, Friends of the Bancroft Library and Gleeson Library Associates materials.
- 1982, 2 items. (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - Morris, Charles Kendrick. Near the Ocean's Edge, poems by Charles Kendrick Morris. San Francisco: Charles Kendrick Morris, 1982. Edition of 200 copies designed and printed by Peter Koch, BSP.
  - Meje, Malles. Shreds. San Francisco: Beatrice Love Kaukonen, 1982.Designed and printed at BSP.
- 1988 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  White, Kerr L., M.D. The Taste of Medicine, Dialogue at Wickenburg. Menlo Park, CA: Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation, 1988. Designed by Peter Koch.
- 1988 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  Soul of the Vine, Wine in Literature. Ed. by Nina Wemyss. Oakville: Robert Mondavi Winery, 1988. Edition of 1100 copies printed by Peter Koch.
- 1988 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  Rutkow, Ira M., M.D. The History of Surgery in the United States, 1775-1900. Vol. 1. Encased in packing plastic.
- Oversized Broadsides
  Arranged by date.
  - 1981
    - "Deadstart," signed by PK.
    - Portfolio for "Faurest Davis Photographs." San Francisco: Paul M. Hertzmann, Inc., 1981.
    - "Golden Gate Paragate Bodhi Svaha"
    - "Word Swords I, Bedrock," 16/26.Signed lithograph by PK.
    - "Word Swords, Woman in Bondage," 4/9.Signed lithograph by PK.
    - "Hommage to Jeanette Rankin," 6/9.Signed lithograph by PK.
  - 1984
    - Robert Duncan. From Ground Work: Before the War (New Directions, 1984).Gift from Black Oak Books, printed by PK.
    - Robert Duncan. From Ground Work: Before the War (New Directions, 1984). Tribute from Black Oak Books to contributers of The Threepenny Review, August 1984.Limited edition of 150 copies printed by PK.
    - Broadside from Alice Waters. Chez Panisse Pasta, Pizza, and Calzone. Gift from Black Oak Books and A Clean Well-Lighted Place for Books, designed by PK. (2 copies, slightly different)
    - ARQ.
    - Christopher Smart, 1763."Of Jeoffry, his cat." Christmas and Chanukah gift from Black Oak Books, Berkeley. Designed and Printed by PK.
    - Christopher Smart, 1763."Of Jeoffry, his cat." Christmas and Chanukah gift from Black Oak Books, Berkeley. Designed and Printed by PK. "One of 50 copies on Rives paper made especially for friends of Black Oak Books."
    - J. H. Mason. "Typography."
    - Molly Gleason. "Blackeyedpeacockbluelightcaféaulait." "Tribute to Boz Scaggs. Fifty copies printed on Rives paper by PK."
    - Epes Ellery, A Book Store. One of 300 copies printed by PK in Oct., 1984.
    - Title page and frontispiece. Mary Stent. Ramayana, a Hindu Epic. From limited print of 25 copies. Printed by PK.
    - "Captured in Words," 11/15.Signed lithograph by PK.
  - 1985
    - Certificate of Dedication of the Emilie Dohrmann Cosgrove Reading Room, California Historical Society.
    - Neil Folberg. "Jerusalem."
    - Exhibit announcement, "the work of the Milan publishers Giovanni Scheiwiller and Vanni Scheiwiller "all' Insegna del Pesce d'Oro" October 7-November 8, 1985,Donohue Rare Book Room, Richard A. Gleeson Library, Univ. of San Francisco. Designed and printed by PK.
    - Poster. "University of San Francisco Symposium XIX: 'Egypt: People of the Sun,'" August 1-3, 1985.Poster design by PK.